Norman Vincent Peale Papers
Norman Vincent Peale Papers
- I. Correspondence
  - B: Special correspondence
    - Joe Levy files
      - Correspondence, 1960
        - Anonymous (Box I:B:162)
        - Books (Box I:B:162)
        - Broadcasting and Film Commission, 1961 (Box I:B:162)
        - Budget, 1961 (Box I:B:162)
        - Church House Building Fund (Box I:B:162)
        - Clinic (Box I:B:162)
        - Collegiate Church, 1962 (Box I:B:162)
        - Column Mail (Box I:B:162)
        - Contributors List (Box I:B:162)
        - Crank Mail (Box I:B:162)
        - Rev. H.T. Donaldson, Summer 1961 (Box I:B:162)
        - Easter Offering (Box I:B:162)
        - Elders and Deacons (Box I:B:162)
        - Employment (Box I:B:162)
        - Foreign Mail (Box I:B:162)
        - F.C.L. (Box I:B:162)
        - Guideposts (Box I:B:162)
        - Illustrations (Box I:B:163)
        - Marble Church Fund Raising, 1961 (Box I:B:163)
        - Marble Times (Box I:B:163)
        - New Members (Box I:B:163)
        - Poems, Songs, Misc. (Box I:B:163)
        - Political Controversy, Fall 1960 (Box I:B:163)
        - P.P.T. - P.P.T. (Box I:B:163)
        - Prayer Requests (Box I:B:163)
        - Prentice-Hall (Box I:B:163)
        - Presbyterian Ministers' Fund (Box I:B:163)
        - 1961 (Box I:B:164)
        - Problems (Box I:B:164)
        - References (Box I:B:164)
        - Reformed Church in America (Box I:B:164)
        - Requests for Gifts (Box I:B:164)
        - Rotary Club (Box I:B:164)
        - Scientific Marriage Foundation (Box I:B:164)
        - Sermon Excerpts Summer Supplies Visitors (Box I:B:164)
    - Leonard Le Sourd file
      This material contains incoming and outgoing correspondence about and by both Dr. Le Sourd and Dr. Peale. It contains letters pertaining to Girls Town, Guideposts, the Hundredth Anniversary, and speaking engagements. This series is arranged chronologically, then alphabetically within each year, and includes some arrangement by subject.
      - Correspondence, 1954
        - A (Box I:B:165)
        - Anonymous (Box I:B:165)
        - B (Box I:B:165)
        - Barbery (Box I:B:165)
        - Benett, Millard (Box I:B:165)
        - Blanton (Box I:B:165)
        - C (Box I:B:165)
        - D (Box I:B:165)
        - Dealey (Box I:B:165)
        - Dedication Services (Chapel, Etc.) (Box I:B:165)
        - Employment Applications (Box I:B:166)
        - European Trip (Box I:B:166)
        - F (Box I:B:166)
        - G (Box I:B:166)
        - Girls' Town (Box I:B:166)
        - Guideposts (Box I:B:166)
        - Halo Christmas (Box I:B:166)
        - H-L (Box I:B:166)
        - M (Box I:B:167)
        - McCall's Magazine (Box I:B:167)
        - N (Box I:B:167)
        - O (Box I:B:167)
        - One Hundredth Anniversary (Box I:B:167)
        - P (Box I:B:167)
        - Peale Associates (Box I:B:167)
        - Peale Personal (Box I:B:167)
        - P.P.T. (answered by H.M.L. and V.J.) (Box I:B:167)
        - P.P.T. Records (R.C.A.) (Box I:B:167)
        - Prayer Correspondence (Box I:B:168)
        - Prentice-Hall (Box I:B:168)
        - R (Box I:B:168)
        - S (Box I:B:168)
        - Sermon Publications (Box I:B:169)
        - Seventeen (Box I:B:169)
        - T (Box I:B:169)
        - V (Box I:B:169)
        - Whan Lee Chang (Box I:B:169)
        - Writing Contributions by N.V.P. (Box I:B:169)
        - W-Z (Box I:B:169)
      - Correspondence, 1955-1956
        - A (Box I:B:169)
        - B-Dd (Box I:B:170)
        - De-G (Box I:B:171)
        - Hb-K (Box I:B:172)
        - L-Pd (Box I:B:173)
        - Pe-So (Box I:B:174)
        - Speaking Engagements (N.V.P. Listing) (Box I:B:175)
        - Speaking A-Z (Box I:B:175)
        - T (Box I:B:175)
        - True Confessions (Box I:B:175)
        - U (Box I:B:175)
        - V (Box I:B:175)
        - W, 1955-1958 (Box I:B:175)
        - W-Z (Box I:B:176)
  - C: Regular correspondence
    Regular correspondence is arranged chronologically and then alphabetically within each year. There is some subject arrangement.
    - Correspondence, 1960
      - A-Co (Box I:C:1)
      - Chaplains (Box I:C:1)
      - Churches (Assembly of God - United, and misc.) (Box I:C:1)
      - Cr-Fl (Box I:C:2)
      - Foreign Correspondence (Box I:C:2)
      - G-Jo (Box I:C:2)
      - K-L (Box I:C:3)
      - Letter B-L (A-L) (Box I:C:3)
      - Letter B-L (M-Z) (Box I:C:3)
      - Li-Me (Box I:C:3)
      - Misc. (Box I:C:3)
      - New York Life Insurance Co. (Box I:C:3)
      - Mo-Pi (Box I:C:3)
      - Promotional material for 1960 and previous years (Box I:C:4)
      - Q-R (Box I:C:4)
      - Receipts (Box I:C:4)
      - Ri-Z (Box I:C:4)
    - Correspondence, 1961
      - A-Bl (Box I:C:5)
      - Books (Box I:C:5)
      - Bro-C (Box I:C:5)
      - Chaplains (Box I:C:5)
      - Churches (Assembly of God United, and misc.) (Box I:C:5)
      - Co (Box I:C:5)
      - Cr-Fl (Box I:C:7)
      - Foreign correspondence (Box I:C:7)
      - G-J (Box I:C:8)
      - Jo-L (Box I:C:9)
      - Letter B-L (A-L) (Box I:C:9)
      - Letter B-L (M-Z) (Box I:C:10)
      - Li-Mo (Box I:C:10)
      - N-R (Box I:C:11)
      - Receipt (Box I:C:11)
      - Ri-S (Box I:C:11)
      - Se-To (Box I:C:12)
      - U-Z (Box I:C:13)
    - Correspondence, 1962
      - A-B (Box I:C:14)
      - Mr. B's Chaps (Box I:C:14)
      - Be-Bl (Box I:C:14)
      - Bro-C (Box I:C:15)
      - Churches (Episcopal - Methodist) (Box I:C:15)
      - Churches (Presbyterian - United, and misc) (Box I:C:16)
      - Co-F (Box I:C:16)
      - Fl (Box I:C:17)
      - Foreign Correspondence (Box I:C:17)
      - G-Gr (Box I:C:17)
      - Guideposts (Box I:C:17)
      - H-I (Box I:C:17)
      - J-L (Box I:C:18)
      - Letter B-L (A-E) (Box I:C:18)
      - Letter B-L (F-P) (Box I:C:18)
      - Letter B-L (R-Z) (Box I:C:19)
      - Li-N (Box I:C:19)
      - New York Life Insurance Co. (Box I:C:19)
      - O-P (Box I:C:19)
      - Pi-R (Box I:C:20)
      - Receipts (Box I:C:20)
      - Ri-Sn (Box I:C:20)
      - Sta-Z (Box I:C:21)
    - Correspondence, 1963
      - A-Bo (Box I:C:22)
      - Books (Box I:C:22)
      - Br-Ch (Box I:C:23)
      - Chaplains (Box I:C:23)
      - Churches (Assembly of God United, and misc.) (Box I:C:23)
      - Cl-Fl (Box I:C:24)
      - Foreign Correspondence (A-L) (Box I:C:24)
      - Foreign Correspondence (M-Z) (Box I:C:25)
      - Fr-Gr (Box I:C:25)
      - Guideposts (Box I:C:25)
      - H-Ho (Box I:C:25)
      - Hom-I (Box I:C:26)
      - Industrial File (Box I:C:26)
      - J-L (Box I:C:26)
      - Letter B-L (A-Z) (Box I:C:26)
      - Lo-N (Box I:C:27)
      - New York Life Insurance Co. (Box I:C:27)
      - Ni-O (Box I:C:27)
      - Ol-Re (Box I:C:28)
      - Receipts (Box I:C:28)
      - Ri-Ros (Box I:C:28)
      - S-T (Box I:C:29)
      - Tw-Z (Box I:C:30)
    - Correspondence, 1964
      - A-Bo (Box I:C:31)
      - Books (A-F) (Box I:C:31)
      - Books (G-Z) (Box I:C:32)
      - Br-Bu (Box I:C:32)
      - Business File (Box I:C:32)
      - C (Box I:C:32)
      - Car-Ch (Box I:C:33)
      - Chaplains (Box I:C:33)
      - Churches (Assembly of God Methodist) (Box I:C:33)
      - Churches (Presbyterian United, and misc.) (Box I:C:34)
      - Co-De (Box I:C:34)
      - Do (Box I:C:35)
      - Dorsam (Box I:C:35)
      - Du-Fl (Box I:C:35)
      - Foreign (Box I:C:36)
      - Fr-Gr (Box I:C:37)
      - Guideposts (Box I:C:37)
      - H (Box I:C:37)
      - Har-J (Box I:C:38)
      - Jo-Le (Box I:C:39)
      - Letter B-L (Box I:C:40)
      - Lo-McL (Box I:C:40)
      - M-Mu (Box I:C:41)
      - N-Re (Box I:C:42)
      - Receipts (Box I:C:43)
      - Ri-Sl (Box I:C:43)
      - Sm-St (Box I:C:44)
      - Studio Girl (Box I:C:44)
      - Sto-V (Box I:C:44)
      - W-Z (Box I:C:45)
- II. Subject files
  Subject files are divided into eleven subseries: A) Prayer correspondence; B) Problem correspondence; C) Look Correspondence; D) Radio file; E) Sermon File; F) Kennedy Campaign; G) Marble Collegiate Church 100th Anniversary; H) Research materials; J) Testimonial dinner; K) Guideposts; and L) Sermon publications. The listing of each subseries below contains a more detailed explanation of its contents.
  - A: Prayer correspondence
    This series contains 1) subject files and 2) prayer letters. Subject files contains correspondence to Dr. Peale, asking for his prayers, lists of prayers available and newspaper clippings pertaining to statements made by Dr. Peale on prayer. Also, there are requests for copies of Dr. Peale's sermons. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by type, then chronologically. Prayer letters contains correspondence to Dr. Peale asking for his prayers or copies of his sermons. These letters are pleas for his prayers to help with problems of illness; both mental and physical, family problems or prayers for loved ones. They are arranged chronologically. Within this arrangement some are also arranged alphabetically.
    - Subject files
      - Group Exchange Prayers, 1959 (Box II:A:1)
      - Letters of Appreciation, 1957-1962 (Box II:A:2)
      - Material Sent
      - Prayer Lists, 1953-1955; 1957-1958 (Box II:A:2)
      - Prayer Lists, 1959-1963 (Box II:A:3)
      - Prayer List - Church, 1961-1962 (Box II:A:4)
      - Prayers Answered (Box II:A:4)
      - Prayers - Clippings, 1962 (Box II:A:4)
      - Sermons Requested and Sent (Box II:A:4)
    - Prayer letters, 1958
      - A-Z and unsigned (Box II:A:5)
      - Prayer letters, 1958, March - Sept. 23 (Box II:A:6)
      - Prayer letters, 1958, Sept. 24 - Oct. 31 (Box II:A:7)
      - Prayer letters, 1958, Nov. - Dec. (Box II:A:8)
    - Prayer letters, 1959
      - A-C (Box II:A:8)
      - D-S (Box II:A:9)
      - T-Z, unsigned (Box II:A:10)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, Jan. 1 - Feb. 6 (Box II:A:10)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, Feb. 7 - Mar. 31 (Box II:A:11)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, Apr. 1 - May 5 (Box II:A:12)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, June 1 - July 31 (Box II:A:13)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, Aug. 1 - Oct. 14 (Box II:A:14)
      - Prayer letters, 1959, Oct 15 - Dec. 31 (Box II:A:15)
    - Prayer letters, 1960-1965
      - A (Box II:A:16)
      - B-Be (Box II:A:17)
      - Be-Bra (Box II:A:18)
      - Bre-By (Box II:A:19)
      - Cad-Chu (Box II:A:20)
      - Ci-Coy (Box II:A:21)
      - Cr-De (Box II:A:22)
      - Di-Ek (Box II:A:23)
      - El-For (Box II:A:24)
      - Fos-Go (Box II:A:25)
      - Gra-Hap (Box II:A:26)
      - Har-Hic (Box II:A:27)
      - Hie-Hy (Box II:A:28)
      - I-Jones (Box II:A:29)
      - Jones-Kl (Box II:A:30)
      - Kn-Le (Box II:A:31)
      - Li-Ma (Box II:A:32)
      - Mac-Martin (Box II:A:33)
      - Martin-Mo (Box II:A:34)
      - Mo-Ne (Box II:A:35)
      - Ni-Pa (Box II:A:36)
      - Pf-Q (Box II:A:37)
      - R-Ro (Box II:A:38)
      - Row-Sha (Box II:A:39)
      - She-Stet (Box II:A:40)
      - Stev-Th (Box II:A:41)
      - Ti-Waite (Box II:A:42)
      - Walto-Wils (Box II:A:43)
      - Wilt-Z (Box II:A:44)
  - B: Problem correspondence
    This series consists of correspondence to Dr. Peale on personal problems and his answers to the writers. In most cases the pleas deal with health or family problems. Some of the problems are concerns: morality, birth control, unfaithful spouses, mental illness, lack of faith, and job losses. Dr. Peale tries to deal with each case and in some of his answers gives direct advice, but in many instances he refers applicants to the American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry, or a competent psychiatrist or minister in their region of the country. The series is arranged chronologically, and within each year, alphabetically by the correspondent.
    - Problem correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box II:B:1)
    - Problem correspondence, A-H, 1949 (Box II:B:2)
    - Problem correspondence, Hannah, Evelyn, 1949 (Box II:B:2)
    - Problem correspondence, I-R, 1949 (Box II:B:2)
    - Problem correspondence, S-W, 1949 (Box II:B:3)
    - Problem correspondence, 1950 (Box II:B:4)
    - Problem correspondence, A-F, 1951 (Box II:B:4)
    - Problem correspondence, G-Z, 1951 (Box II:B:5)
    - Problem correspondence, A-K, 1952 (Box II:B:6)
    - Problem correspondence, L-Z, 1952 (Box II:B:7)
    - Problem correspondence, 1953 (Box II:B:8)
    - Problem correspondence, 1954
      - A-B (Box II:B:8)
      - B-E (Box II:B:9)
      - F-J (Box II:B:10)
      - K-L (Box II:B:11)
      - Answers by LeSourd, A-O (Box II:B:11)
      - Answers by LeSourd, P-Z (Box II:B:12)
      - M-O (Box II:B:12)
      - P-S (Box II:B:13)
      - T-Z (Box II:B:14)
    - Problem correspondence, 1955
      - A-F (Box II:B:15)
      - Mr. Elliot's Letters (Box II:B:15)
      - G-H (Box II:B:15)
      - I-W (Box II:B:16)
      - Rose Weiss' Letters, typed from belts (Box II:B:17)
      - Y-Z (Box II:B:17)
    - Problem correspondence, 1958-1959
      - A-J (Box II:B:17)
      - K-Z (Box II:B:18)
      - A-H (Box II:B:18)
      - J-Z (Box II:B:19)
      - A-O (Box II:B:19)
      - P-Z (Box II:B:20)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:20)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:20)
      - A-D (Box II:B:20)
      - E-R (Box II:B:21)
      - S-Z (Box II:B:22)
      - A-K (Box II:B:22)
      - L-Z (Box II:B:23)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:23)
    - Problem correspondence, 1959-1960
      - A-Z (Box II:B:24)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:24)
      - A-G (Box II:B:24)
      - H-Z (Box II:B:25)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:25)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:25)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:26)
      - A-O (Box II:B:26)
      - P-Z (Box II:B:27)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:27)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:28)
      - A-Z (Box II:B:28)
      - A-F (Box II:B:28)
      - G-Z (Box II:B:29)
      - No reply (Box II:B:29)
    - Problem correspondence, 1960
      - A-B (Box II:B:30)
      - B-C (Box II:B:31)
      - C-E (Box II:B:32)
      - E-G (Box II:B:33)
      - G-H (Box II:B:34)
      - H-K (Box II:B:35)
      - K-L (Box II:B:36)
      - L-M (Box II:B:37)
      - M-P (Box II:B:38)
      - P-R (Box II:B:39)
      - R-S (Box II:B:40)
      - S-T (Box II:B:41)
      - U-Z (Box II:B:42)
    - Problem correspondence, 1963-1965
      - A-Z (Box II:B:43)
      - Ba-Br (Box II:B:44)
      - Bu-Con (Box II:B:45)
      - Coo-D (Box II:B:46)
      - E-Gi (Box II:B:47)
      - Gl-Haz (Box II:B:48)
      - He-J (Box II:B:49)
      - K-Le (Box II:B:50)
      - Li-Me (Box II:B:51)
      - Mi-O (Box II:B:52)
      - P (Box II:B:53)
      - Q-Sa (Box II:B:54)
      - Sca-Stel (Box II:B:55)
      - Stem-V (Box II:B:56)
      - W-Z (Box II:B:57)
  - C: Look correspondence
    This series contains 1) subject files and 2) general correspondence. There is both incoming and outgoing correspondence. Subject files includes correspondence containing questions submitted to Dr. Peale for his Look magazine column. Included is a summary of the type of problems submitted. Among these are letters dealing with divorce, homosexuality, faith, in-laws, death, politics, and personality. These are arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically by year. General correspondence includes correspondence dealing with specific subjects submitted by the general public to Dr. Peale. Some of the problems in the correspondence include domestic problems such as infidelity and divorce, religion, politics, health, love, youth, and alcoholism. The file is arranged chronologically and within each year, numerically -- using a number code for problem categories.
    - Subject file
      - Clinic correspondence, 1957 (Box II:C:1)
      - Clinic correspondence, homosexuals, 1956 (Box II:C:1)
      - Faith experiences (Box II:C:1)
      - Letters from readers who use positive thinking, 1959 (Box II:C:1)
      - Letter possibilities for radio talks (Box II:C:1)
      - Look finance reports, 1958 (Box II:C:1)
      - Look finance reports, 1959 (Box II:C:1)
      - Look questions and answers submitted, 1954-1959 (Box II:C:2)
      - Look question possibilities, 1954 (Box II:C:2)
      - Look question possibilities, 1955-1958 (Box II:C:3)
      - Prayer requests, 1960 (Box II:C:4)
      - Summary of Look correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box II:C:4)
      - Special letter folder, 1958-1960 (Box II:C:4)
    - General correspondence
      - Look correspondence, 1954 (Box II:C:5)
      - General correspondence, 1955
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:6)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:7)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:8)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:9)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:10)
        - Infidelity (Box II:C:10)
        - Infidelity (Box II:C:11)
        - Divorce (Box II:C:11)
        - In-Laws (Box II:C:11)
        - Religion (Box II:C:12)
        - Religion (Box II:C:13)
        - Religion (Box II:C:14)
        - Occupations and employment (Box II:C:14)
        - Politics (Box II:C:14)
        - General information (Box II:C:14)
        - General information (Box II:C:15)
        - General information (Box II:C:16)
        - Health (Box II:C:17)
        - Death (Box II:C:18)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:18)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:19)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:20)
        - Love problems (Box II:C:21)
        - Youth (Box II:C:21)
        - Youth (Box II:C:22)
        - Alcohol (Box II:C:22)
        - Criticisms, testimonials (Box II:C:23)
        - Subscription, book inquiries (Box II:C:24)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:24)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:25)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:26)
        - Old age problems (Box II:C:26)
        - Look permission folder (Box II:C:26)
      - General correspondence, 1956
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:27)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:28)
        - Domestic problems (Box II:C:29)
        - Infidelity (Box II:C:29)
        - Divorce (Box II:C:29)
        - Divorce (Box II:C:30)
        - In-Laws (Box II:C:30)
        - Religion (Box II:C:30)
        - Religion (Box II:C:31)
        - Occupation and employment (Box II:C:32)
        - Politics (Box II:C:32)
        - General information (Box II:C:32)
        - General information (Box II:C:33)
        - Health (Box II:C:34)
        - Death (Box II:C:34)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:34)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:35)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:36)
        - Love problems (Box II:C:36)
        - Youth (Box II:C:37)
        - Alcohol (Box II:C:37)
        - Alcohol (Box II:C:38)
        - Criticisms and testimonials (Box II:C:38)
        - General criticisms (Box II:C:39)
        - Racial and religious criticisms (Box II:C:39)
        - Comments (Box II:C:39)
        - Subscriptions and book inquiries (Box II:C:39)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:40)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:41)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:42)
        - Old age problems (Box II:C:42)
        - Premarital relations (Box II:C:42)
        - No Name or Address (Box II:C:42)
        - Unsorted (Box II:C:42)
        - Unsorted (Box II:C:43)
        - Look Personal Reply, Jan-Jun 1956; Jul-Sep 1956, A-L (Box II:C:44)
        - Look Personal Reply, Jul-Sep 1956, M-Z; Oct-Dec 1956, A-Z (Box II:C:45)
      - General correspondence, 1957
        - General Information (Box II:C:46)
        - General Information (Box II:C:47)
        - Health (Box II:C:47)
        - Health (Box II:C:48)
        - Death (Box II:C:48)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:48)
        - Personality problems (Box II:C:49)
        - Love problems (Box II:C:49)
        - Youth (Box II:C:49)
        - Youth (Box II:C:50)
        - Sub-Teens (Box II:C:50)
        - Alcohol (Box II:C:51)
        - Criticisms and testimonials (Box II:C:51)
        - Criticisms and testimonials (Box II:C:52)
        - Comments (Box II:C:52)
        - Criticisms of Darwin's Theory (Box II:C:52)
        - Religious and racial criticisms (Box II:C:52)
        - Criticisms (Box II:C:53)
        - Book inquiries (Box II:C:53)
        - No answer sent (Box II:C:53)
        - Old age problems (Box II:C:53)
        - Premarital relations (Box II:C:53)
        - No Name, No Address (Box II:C:53)
        - No Name, No Address (Box II:C:54)
        - Unsorted (Box II:C:54)
        - Unsorted (Box II:C:55)
        - D-F (Box II:C:55)
        - G-M (Box II:C:56)
        - N-V (Box II:C:57)
      - General correspondence, 1958
        - Marital-Domestic A-G (Box II:C:58)
        - Marital-Domestic, H-R (Box II:C:59)
        - Marital-Domestic, S-Z (Box II:C:60)
        - Marital-Domestic, unsorted (Box II:C:60)
        - Marital-Domestic, unsorted (Box II:C:61)
        - Religion, A-G (Box II:C:61)
        - Religion, H-W, unsorted (Box II:C:62)
        - Religion, unsorted (Box II:C:63)
        - Health, A-F (Box II:C:63)
        - Health, G-M (Box II:C:64)
        - Health, N-Z, unsorted (Box II:C:65)
        - Death (Box II:C:66)
        - Old Age (Box II:C:66)
        - Youth, A-J (Box II:C:66)
        - Youth, K-Z (Box II:C:67)
        - Juvenile Delinquency (Box II:C:67)
        - Misc. Letters, A-B (Box II:C:68)
        - Misc. Letters, C-K (Box II:C:69)
        - Misc. Letters, L-R (Box II:C:70)
        - Misc. Letters, S-Z (Box II:C:71)
        - Testimonials (Box II:C:72)
        - Comments and Criticisms, unsorted (Box II:C:72)
        - Comments and Criticisms, A-M (Box II:C:73)
        - Comments and Criticisms, N-Z (Box II:C:74)
        - No Reply Letters (Box II:C:74)
        - Old Files (Box II:C:75)
        - Look Correspondence, unsorted (Box II:C:75)
        - Look Correspondence, unsorted (Box II:C:76)
        - Domestic, A-O (Box II:C:76)
        - Domestic, P-Z (Box II:C:77)
        - Religion (Box II:C:77)
        - Health (Box II:C:78)
        - Death (Box II:C:78)
        - Old Age (Box II:C:78)
        - Youth, A-D (Box II:C:78)
        - Youth, E-Z (Box II:C:79)
        - Misc., A-R (Box II:C:79)
        - Misc., S-Z (Box II:C:80)
        - Testimonials (Box II:C:80)
        - Comments (Box II:C:80)
        - No Reply (Box II:C:80)
        - No Name, No Address (Box II:C:80)
      - General correspondence, 1959
        - Domestic, A-O (Box II:C:81)
        - Domestic, P-Z (Box II:C:82)
        - Religion, A-R (Box II:C:82)
        - Religion, S-Z (Box II:C:83)
        - Health (Box II:C:83)
        - Death (Box II:C:83)
        - Old Age (Box II:C:84)
        - Youth (Box II:C:84)
        - Misc., A-D (Box II:C:84)
        - Misc, E-Z (Box II:C:85)
        - Testimonials, A-M (Box II:C:85)
        - Testimonials, N-Z (Box II:C:86)
        - Comments (Box II:C:86)
        - No Reply (Box II:C:86)
  - D: Radio files
    This material includes correspondence requesting copies of Dr. Peale's broadcasts "The Art of Living" and receipts for donations received to help him carry on this work. Included in the correspondence are appeal letters written by Captain Eddie Rickenbacker on behalf of Dr. Peale. Also included are manuscripts and discs of Dr. Peale's radio sermons. The correspondence from listeners includes questions to Dr. Peale on such subjects as alcoholism, divorce, sex, business and finance, grief, marriage difficulties, and personality problems. The material is arranged chronologically and then alphabetically within the year.
    - Broadcasting and Film Commission, 1950-1953 (Box II:D:1)
    - Financial file, 1954 (Box II:D:1)
    - Financial file, 1955-1957 (Box II:D:2)
    - Contributions
      - Appeal Letters, 1954-1960 (Box II:D:2)
      - Appeal Letters, W.B. Wallace (Box II:D:2)
      - Form Letter, 1956 (Box II:D:2)
      - List of Contributions
        - Small, 1940 (Box II:D:3)
        - Large, 1954; 1956 (Box II:D:3)
        - Large, $25 and up, 1956 (Box II:D:4)
        - Over $5, 1957 (Box II:D:4)
        - Receipts (Box II:D:4)
    - Radio correspondence
      - Radio correspondence, A-R, 1938 (Box II:D:5)
      - Radio correspondence, S-Z and Unidentifiable, 1938 (Box II:D:6)
      - Radio correspondence, 1940
        - A-D (Box II:D:6)
        - E-P (Box II:D:7)
        - Q-Z, and unidentifiable (Box II:D:8)